Finding Aid for Postum Company records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Postum Company records 1895-1931
Postum Company
1 reel of Microfilm
164 oversize volumes
17 linear feet
852064 BB.1 Bb.1 2
Records, 1895-1931, of the Postum Cereal Company of Battle Creek, founded by Charles W. Post; include time books, payrolls, invoice and voucher records, trial balances, cash receipts registers, and sales and advertising material.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donor: 3464
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Post Cereals, formerly Postum Cereals, was founded by C. W. Post. It began in 1895 with the first Postum, a "cereal beverage", developed by Post in Battle Creek, Michigan. The first cereal, Grape-Nuts, was developed in 1897.
The Postum Company records are an incomplete set of employment and financial records covering the period 1895-1931. The records have been described in two series: Payroll and Employee Records and financial and Miscellaneous Records. The records include employee time books, payrolls, invoice and voucher records, trial balances, cash receipts registers, and sales and advertising material.
The collection includes 164 outsize volumes. A unique sequential number (1-166, there is no vol. no. 91 or 92) has been assigned to each volume to aid in identification and location of the volumes. This number is given at the beginning of descriptive entry in the contents list. Some volumes had a number or letter stamped on the spine. This number is listed in square brackets at the end of the item entry.
Subjects:
Battle Creek (Mich.); Cereal products industry--United States.; Business records.; General Foods Corporation.; Post, Charles William, 1854-1914.
- Payroll and Employee Records
  - Carton and Container Department 1908-1928
    - Payroll ledger sheets
      - [A-B] (Box 1)
      - [C-E] (Box 2)
      - [F-G] (Box 3)
      - [H-K] (Box 4)
      - [L-M] (Box 5)
      - [N-P] (Box 6)
      - [S] (Box 7)
      - [T-Z] (Box 8)
  - Transfer Time book 1902-1909
    - [A-L] (Box 9)
    - [M-Z] (Box 10)
  - Employees bonus ledger
    - 1909-1920 (Box 11)
  - Battle Creek Paper Company
    - Employee Bonus ledger 1908-1909 (Box 14)
    - Time book 1907-1928 (Box 14)
  - Payroll books
    - March-October 1896 [A] (Box 14)
    - October-December 1896 [B] (Box 14)
    - January-March 1897 [C] (Box 14)
    - March-May 1897 [D] (Box 14)
    - May 1897-February 1898 [E] (Box 14)
    - February-December 1898 [F] (Box 14)
    - December 1898-April 1899 [G] (Box 14)
    - July 1901-March 1902 (Box 15)
    - March-September 1902 (Box 15)
    - September 1902-January 1903 (Box 15)
    - January-July 1903 (Box 15)
    - July 1903-January 1904 (Box 15)
    - January-June 1904 (Box 15)
    - December 1904-May 1905 (Box 15)
    - May-October 1905 (Box 15)
    - October 1905-April 1906 (Box 15)
    - April-October 1906 (Box 15)
    - October 1906-Mar-1907 (Box 15)
    - March-August 1907 (Box 15)
    - August-December 1907 (Box 15)
  - Male employees time book
    - January-July, 1897 [1] (Box 16)
    - July 1897-August 1898 [2] (Box 16)
    - August-December 1898 [3] (Box 16)
  - Packing room time book
    - February-June 1897 [3] (Box 16)
    - June-July 1902 [9] (Box 16)
  - Payroll Books (Bound Volumes)
    (Outsize volumes in Annex except for 24 volumes located in BB.1 Outsize)
    - May 1899-May 1900 [H], 1 (Volume 1)
    - May 1900-January 1901 [I], 2 (Volume 2)
    - February-September 1901 [J], 3 (Volume 3)
    - October 1901-May 1902 [K], 4 (Volume 4)
    - May-November 1902 [L], 5 (Volume 5)
    - November 1902-July 1903 [M], 6 (Volume 6)
    - July 1903-February 1904 [N], 7 (Volume 7)
    - February-October 1904 [O], 8 (Volume 8)
    - October 1904-June 1905 [P], 9 (Volume 9)
    - June 1905-January 1906 [Q], 10 (Volume 10)
    - January-August 1906 [R], 11 (Volume 11)
    - August 1906-April 1907 [S], 12 (Volume 12)
    - April-October 1907 [T], 13 (Volume 13)
    - October 1907-October 1908 [1], 14 (Volume 14)
    - October 1907-March 1909 [2], 15 (Volume 15)
    - October 1908-October 1909 [3], 16 (Volume 16)
    - March 1909-July 1910 [4], 17 (Volume 17)
    - October 1909-November 1910 [5], 18 (Volume 18)
    - July 1910-April 1912 [6], 19 (Volume 19)
    - November 1910-December 1911 [7], 20 (Volume 20)
    - May 1912-November 1913 [8], 21 (Volume 21)
    - December 1911-October 1912 [9], 22 (Volume 22)
    - December 1913-May 1915 [10], 23 (Volume 23)
    - October 1912-July 1913 [11], 24 (Volume 24)
    - August 1913-May 1914 [12], 25 (Volume 25)
    - May 1914-March 1915 [14], 26 (Volume 26)
    - March-December 1915 [15], 27 (Volume 27)
    - May 1915-July 1916 [16], 28 (Volume 28)
    - December 1915-August, 1916 [17], 29 (Volume 29)
    - July 1916-June 1917 [18], 30 (Volume 30)
    - August 1916-May 1917 [19], 31 (Volume 31)
    - November 1916-June 1918 [20], 32 (Volume 32)
    - May 1917-April 1918 [21], 33 (Volume 33)
    - July 1917-May 1918 [22], 34 (Volume 34)
    - May 1918-February 1919 [23], 35 (Volume 35)
    - May 1918-September 1919 [24], 36 (Volume 36)
    - May 1918-June 1919 [25], 37 (Volume 37)
    - June 1918-May 1920 [26], 38 (Volume 38)
    - February-November 1919 [27], 39 (Volume 39)
    - June 1919-May 1920 [28], 40 (Volume 40)
    - September 1919-February 1921 [29], 41 (Volume 41)
    - November 1919-June 1920 [30], 42 (Volume 42)
    - May 1920-December 1921 [31], 43 (Volume 43)
    - May 1920-June 1921 [32], 44 (Volume 44)
    - June 1920-February 1921 [33], 45 (Volume 45)
    - February-December 1921 [34], 46 (Volume 46)
    - February-November 1921 [35], 47 (Volume 47)
    - June-December 1921 [36], 48 (Volume 48)
    - December 1921-May 1924 [37], 49 (Volume 49)
    - May 1924-October 1926 [38], 50 (Volume 50)
    - October 1926-July 1928 [45], 51 (Volume 51)
    - July 1928-August 1929 [47], 52 (Volume 52)
    - August 1929-December 1930 [51], 53 (Volume 53)
    - January-December 1931 [54], 54 (Volume 54)
  - Cash receipts 1907-1917
    - District 1, 1 volumes; 55 (Volume 55)
    - District 1, 1 volumes; 56 (Volume 56)
      (continued)
    - District 1, 1 volumes; 57 (Volume 57)
    - District 1, 1 volumes; 58 (Volume 58)
    - District 1, 1 volumes; 59 (Volume 59)
    - District 2, 1 volumes; 60 (Volume 60)
    - District 2, 1 volumes; 61 (Volume 61)
    - District 2, 1 volumes; 62 (Volume 62)
    - District 2, 1 volumes; 63 (Volume 63)
    - District 2, 1 volumes; 64 (Volume 64)
    - District 2, 1 volumes; 65 (Volume 65)
    - District 2, 1 volumes; 66 (Volume 66)
    - District 3, 1 volumes; 67 (Volume 67)
    - District 3, 1 volumes; 68 (Volume 68)
    - District 3, 1 volumes; 69 (Volume 69)
    - District 3, 1 volumes; 70 (Volume 70)
    - District 3, 1 volumes; 71 (Volume 71)
    - District 3, 1 volumes; 72 (Volume 72)
    - District 3, 1 volumes; 73 (Volume 73)
    - District 3, 1 volumes; 74 (Volume 74)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 75 (Volume 75)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 76 (Volume 76)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 77 (Volume 77)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 78 (Volume 78)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 79 (Volume 79)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 80 (Volume 80)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 81 (Volume 81)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 82 (Volume 82)
    - District 4, 1 volumes; 83 (Volume 83)
    - District 5, 1 volumes; 84 (Volume 84)
  - Cash receipts, Canadian Postum. Cereal Company 1910-1922
    - 1 volume, 85 (Volume 85)
    - 1 volume, 86 (Volume 86)
    - 1 volume, 87 (Volume 87)
    - 1 volume, 88 (Volume 88)
  - Register of Disbursements 1907-1908, 1 volumes; 89 (Volume 89)
  - Register of Disbursements 1907-1908, 1 volumes; 90 (Volume 90)
  - Petty cash disbursements 1907-1918, 163; 1 volumes
    (BB.1/outsize)
  - Petty cash disbursements 1907-1918, 164; 1 volumes
  - Cash receipts 1917-1921
    - District 1, 93 (Volume 93)
    - District 1, 96 (Volume 96)
    - District 2, 97-101 (Volume 97)
    - District 2, 98 (Volume 98)
    - District 2, 99 (Volume 99)
    - District 2, 100 (Volume 100)
    - District 2, 101 (Volume 101)
    - District 3
      - (Volume 1)
        (BB.1/Outsize)
      - Volume 2, 102 (Volume 102)
      - Volume 3a, 103 (Volume 103)
      - Volume 3b, 104 (Volume 104)
      - Volume 4, 105 (Volume 105)
      - Volume 5, 106 (Volume 106)
      - Volume 6, 107 (Volume 107)
    - District 4, 108 (Volume 108)
    - District 4, 109 (Volume 109)
    - District 4, 110 (Volume 110)
    - District 4, 111 (Volume 111)
    - District 4, 112 (Volume 112)
    - District 5, 113 (Volume 113)
    - District 5, 114 (Volume 114)
    - District 5, 115 (Volume 115)
    - District 5, 116 (Volume 116)
  - Male employees time book
    - December 1898-December 1899 [4], 117 (Volume 117)
    - December 1899-August 1900 [5], 118 (Volume 118)
    - August 1900-February 1901 [6], 119 (Volume 119)
    - March-August 1901 [7], 120 (Volume 120)
    - August 1901-January 1902 [8], 121 (Volume 121)
    - January-July 1902 [9], 122 (Volume 122)
  - Packing room time book
    - September 1897-September 1899 [5], 123 (Volume 123)
    - September 1899-October 1900 [6], 124 (Volume 124)
    - October 1900-July 1901 171, 125 (Volume 125)
    - July 1901-June 1902 [8], 126 (Volume 126)
  - Battle Creek Paper Company Payroll
    (BB.1/Outsize, except for 142)
    - September 1916-August 1919, 154 (Volume 154)
    - September 1919-September 1920, 155 (Volume 155)
    - October 1920-December 1922, 156 (Volume 156)
    - 1923, 157 (Volume 157)
    - 1924, 158 (Volume 158)
    - 1925, 159 (Volume 159)
    - 1926, 160 (Volume 160)
    - 1927, 161 (Volume 161)
    - 1928, 142 (Volume 142)
- Financial and Miscellaneous Records
  - Loan and Bond register 1899-1910 (Box 12)
  - Abstract of expenditures for raw materials 1907-1917 (Box 12)
  - Canadian Postum Cereal Company, Advertising Department Ledger 1910-1921 (Box 13)
  - Bonus book 1906-1908 (Box 13)
  - Packing room records
    - July 1913-September 1914 (Box 16)
    - September 1914-September 1916 (Box 16)
    - September 1916-June 1918 (Box 16)
    - January 1920-September 1921 (Box 16)
    - September 1921-May 1922 (Box 16)
  - Feed book
    - May 1913-January 1916 (Box 16)
    - January 1916-April 1918 (Box 16)
    - January 1920-May 1921 (Box 16)
  - Cost Journal 1918-1922 (Box 16)
  - Sales and Advertising Chart January-June 1921 and Yearly exhibit for 1921, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Analytical exhibit of cumulative costs of operating fuel cars, 1923-1924
    - December 1923 (Box 17)
    - June 1924 (Box 17)
    - December 1924 (Box 17)
  - Record of salaries paid to field staff 1924 (Box 17)
  - Proof of miscellaneous accounts for auditors
    - Trial balance 1924 (Box 17)
  - Advertising Department statements
    - June 1921 (Box 17)
    - July 1921 (Box 17)
    - May 1924 (Box 17)
    - June 1924 (Box 17)
    - July 1924 (Box 17)
    - December 1924, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Correspondence concerning insurance on salesmen outside Michigan 1918-1919 (Box 17)
  - Record of field staff insurance claims 1919-1920, 5 folders (Box 17)
  - Central National Bank Register 1913-1917, 1 volumes; 127 (Volume 127)
  - Central National Bank Register 1913-1917, 1 volumes; 128 (Volume 128)
  - Continental and Commercial Bank of Chicago Register 1913-1917, 1 volumes; 129 (Volume 129)
  - Continental and Commercial Bank of Chicago Register 1913-1917, 1 volumes; 130 (Volume 130)
  - Continental and Commercial Bank of Chicago Register 1913-1917, 1 volumes; 131 (Volume 131)
  - Bank of America, New York, register 1913-1915, 132 (Volume 132)
  - The Dominion Bank of Windsor Ontario register 1909-1919
    - Volume 1, 166
    - Volume 2, 133 (Volume 133)
  - Trial balance
    - 1901, 134 (Volume 134)
    - 1901-1902, 135 (Volume 135)
  - Advertising Department Ledger 1899, 136 (Volume 136)
  - Conditional rebates
    - 1897-1899, 137 (Volume 137)
    - 1899-1900, 138 (Volume 138)
    - 1900-1901, 139 (Volume 139)
  - Sample of form letters produced by advertising department, 140 (Volume 140)
  - Advertising Department
    - Voucher Record 1918-1920, 141 (Volume 141)
  - Record of invoices passed
    - September 1902-April 1904 [1], 144 (Volume 144)
    - April, 1904-July 1905 [2], 145 (Volume 145)
    - July 1905-August 1906 [3], 146 (Volume 146)
    - August 1906-April 1907 [4], 147 (Volume 147)
    - April 1907-August 1907 [5], 148 (Volume 148)
  - Voucher register and distribution of accounts of Canadian Postum Cereal Company, Ltd.
    - 1917-1920, 153 (Volume 153)
    - 1921-1925, 162 (Volume 162)
  - Advertising Department
    - Journal 1918-1919, 148 (Volume 148)
    - Journal 1919, 149 (Volume 149)
    - Journal, (Canadian Postum) 1915-1922, 150 (Volume 150)
    - Invoice book 1918-1919, 151 (Volume 151)
    - Invoice book 1919, 152 (Volume 152)
  - Financial Journals April-December 1895, June-September 1896, 1 microfilms (Reel 1)
    [mf: BB.1; Originals at the Post Division, General Foods Corp., Battle Creek]